Rushi Patel

Summary

Oracle certified associate with almost 4 years of work experience in IT industry. Developer and mentor at the Google Developer Student Club at Dalhousie University. Dedicated speaker skilled in influencing students through effective teaching sessions on the topics of my interest.

Technical Skills

Languages: Java, C#, Python, Gherkin, HTML5, CSS3

Databases: SQL (MySQL), MongoDB, Firebase, DynamoDB, Graph DB(Neo4j)

Frameworks/Libraries: Selenium WebDriver, Junit, NUnit, Springboot, JPA Hibernate, BDD Specflow, Spring MVC, React.js, Node.js, Material UI, Flask, ASP.NET, Flask

Tools and Technologies: AWS (EC2, Cognito, SNS, SQS, API Gateway, Lambda, S3, Lex, Secret Manager, VPC, RDS Aurora), Docker, Webpack, npm scripts, JSON, RESTful API, Git, CI/CD, IntelliJ, PyCharm, VS Code, GCP, Chrome DevTools, Postman, Jenkins, Jira, SonarQube

Education

Master of Applied Computer Science

Dalhousie University

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Engineering

Gujarat Technological University (CGPA: 8.09)

September 2021 – Expected May 2023 Halifax, NS, Canada

> July 2013 – June 2017 Ahmedabad, Gujarat, India

Experience

Teaching Assistant - CSCI 3130 Software Engineering

-

April 2022 - Present

Faculty of Computer Science, Dalhousie University

- Involved in the development of new material for department courses by contributing to the creation of appropriate teaching materials to ensure that content and delivery methods satisfy learning objectives.
- Conducted labs for Test-driven development, Solid Principles, Design Patterns, Code Smells and Gitflow workflow.
- Provided timely and frequent feedback to students, fostering an environment of open communication and interest in discovery.

QA Engineer

Ness Technologies

September 2020 – July 2021

Mumbai, India

- Configuring **SonarQube** and **SauceLabs** for executing scripts in parallel and cross browser testing and utilising SonarQube for automated static code analysis.
- As the only Automation Test Engineer in the project, developed a standalone project in Java to compare and list files (with details of all the files) from different AmazonS3 servers using AWS integrated with Apache Maven dependencies.

Associate Consultant

Capgemini

June 2020 – September 2020 Mumbai, India

- Designed and implemented the automation framework of Chubb small commercial marketplace application by using **Selenium WebDriver**, **NUnit**.
- Used Data Driven Framework to check the behavior of application with different inputs as parameters using Selenium.
- Followed agile methodology and implemented clean code practices, **SOLID** principles, and **Test-Driven Development** using **BDD Specflow**.

Sr. Software Engineer

Capgemini

October 2017 – June 2020

Mumbai, India

- Deploying the code in test as well in production environments with an added responsibility to merge the code using Tortoise SVN/Bitbucket.
- Responsible for creating the controllers and services to get the response using **Spring MVC** Framework and **Hibernate**.

Projects | More Projects on GitHub

Igloodoor - Complete Password Security

- Planned, designed, developed, and deployed a responsive cloud-based web application that handles complete
 password management that ensures the safest password by increasing the average password security by 65%
 in an agile environment.
- Used AWS services (Cloud Formation, Cognito, EC2, S3, VPC, Lambda, RDS, API Gateway) and integrated these services to run the application on AWS infrastructure.

Smarticle - Smart Article Application

Led an agile team to plan, design, develop and deploy a responsive web application that lets users to create, display, follow articles based on users' preference using **Springboot**, and **JPA**.

- Built RESTful APIs to interact with Twitter to get real time tweet data of the articles using Twitter 4j and utilized JWT for user authentication.
- Created and maintained integration pipeline in Heroku and GitHub for CI/CD. Managed source code using Git
 version control and adhered GitFlow branching strategy for on-time release.

Certifications **Achievements** Oracle Certified Associate Java Professional Customer Delight Award - Capgemini 2018 2019 Rising Star Award - Capgemini 2019 **ITIL Foundation** 2018 Star of the month - Capgemini 2020 University Champion – Table Tennis 2013-2015 State Champion – Table Tennis 2014-2015 College Champion - Soccer 2014-2017